（ナルト）あれは…。
十尾の人柱力だってばよ。
That's...
...the Ten Tails Jinchuriki!
akari ga oreba kage ga dekiru to itta
You said if there's light, there are shadow
ano hi no kimi no koe ga wasure rarezu ni
I can't forget the words you said that day
tsuyoku aritai to negai
I wish to be strong
rousoku wo keshita yubi
I put out the candle with my finger
hi no watsusa ni inochi wo oboete
The heat of the flames reminded me of life
boku no koa ga hajikeru
The core of my being bursts open
guren no ai ga kokoro wo yaite
This red-hot love burns my heart
kaze ni mayoe ba namida ga ochiru
While wandering in the wind, tears start to fall
kizutsuki nagara mirai shinjite
Though I'm hurt, I believe in the future
mata saki e sono saki e
Let's go further and further ahead
gareki no sora wa bokura no kizuna
The rubble in the sky is our bond
osou mayakashi kechirashite yaru
I'll cut through the attempts to deceive me
tatakai no hate ni nani mo nakutemo
Even if there's nothing at the end of the battle
mata saki e sono saki e Ikou
Let's go further and further ahead
The Ten Tails' Jinchuriki
十尾が消えた…。
The Ten Tails disappeared?
What's going on?
Did they defeat it?
どうなってる　やっつけたのか？
No...
（ヒアシ）いや。
（サクラ）ヒナタ　見てた？
Hinata! Did you see it?
（ヒナタ）うん。
何がどうなったのか説明できる？
Yeah!
Can you explain
what happened?
Ten Tails was completely
absorbed into that man.
（ヒナタ）あの人に　十尾が
すべて吸収されてしまって…。
チャクラから見ても…。
Based on looking at its chakra.
じゃあ　まさか…。
Don't tell me...
That's the Ten Tails'...
（サスケ）あれが　十尾の…。
人柱力だと？
Jinchuriki?
What is this?!
《扉間：な　なんだ　これは…》
《柱間：まずいのう
人柱力とは…》
This is bad.
Jinchuriki, huh?
He looks even creepier
than before!
ますます気味わりいってばよ。
（ミナト）オビト…。
Obito...
Naruto...
ナルト　なぜ　ヤツが人柱力だとわかる？
How can you tell
he's a Jinchuriki?
俺は　尾獣たちと仲よくなった。
I've become friends
with the Tailed Beasts.
They gave me some
of their chakra earlier,
そんとき　アイツらから
チャクラもらってっから　ハッキリわかる。
so it's obvious to me.
尾獣たちのチャクラが　次々　オビトの中へ
入っていったのを感じられた。
I could sense the Tailed Beasts' chakra
getting sucked into Obito
one after the other.
それに俺ってば長門が
六道の生き返りの術をするのを→
Plus, I've seen Nagato do that
Six Paths Rebirth Jutsu before.
１回見てる。
そもそも　術の印が全然違う。
But the signs he was weaving
were completely different!
とにかく　アイツは　はじめっから
人柱力になる術をしていたんだよ。
Anyway, he was performing
the jutsu
to become a Jinchuriki
all this time.
そうか。
I see...
《キラービー：八っつあんよ
あれが　最終形態か？》
Eight-o! Is that the final form?
No, it's not.
（牛鬼）いや　違う。
ややこしいがあれじゃない。
It's hard to explain,
but that isn't it.
Looks like Ten Tails was
used to create a Jinchuriki
どうやら　最終形態前で
人柱力に利用されやがった。
before it reached its final form.
フン！
Even if you have become
a Jinchuriki,
《たとえ　人柱力になろうとも
明神門は継続中ぞ》
the Gracious Deity Gates
are still in play.
Whoa! Amazing!
すげえ！
No...
いや…。
むっ！？
The Sage Art Seal that
suppressed the Ten Tails was...
《十尾を止めていた
仙法の封印を…》
Such power...
《ヒルゼン：ここまでとは…》
What?!
Impossible!
（ガイ）バカな…　あの四赤陽陣を！
The Four Crimson Rays Formation!
Is it just me,
でかいときより
強くなってねえか？
or is he stronger than
when he was gigantic?
気のせいか？
Before, it was just throwing
its power around.
ただ力を
ぶちまけるだけの前とは違う。
But now, it's learned to focus it.
力を集中できるように
なったみてぇだ。
（ヒアシ）皆の者　気を抜くな！
Everyone, keep your guard up!
We don't know what that man,
向こうで十尾の力を
我がものとした輩が現れた！
who made the Ten Tails' power
his own, might do!
何をするかわからぬぞ！
結界を壊しおった！
He's broken the barrier!
Enough! Obito, stop this!
やめろ　オビト！　もうやめるんだ！
O... bi... to?
（オビト）オ…　ビ…　ト？
I'll be blunt.
This guy is stronger than me!
はっきり言う。
こやつは俺より強い。
No offense,
but it appears so.
失礼ですが　そのようですな。
Even if you reabsorb
your remaining clones,
消え損ねた分身をよこしても
相手にならんぞ　兄者。
you're no match, Elder Brother!
I know.
わかっておる。
However...
だが…。
It would be fun to watch
all the Hokage beg for mercy,
（マダラ）尻込みする火影どもが
見られるのは楽しいが→
but I cannot wait any longer.
待ってもいられなくなったな。
Obito is now just like
the Sage of Six Paths.
《六道仙人と同じになったオビトだ。
I can't let him take the lead
before I use my trump card.
奥の手を使う前に
先を越されかねん》
えっ！
What's happened?
何だ！？
《速い！》
He's so fast!
Saru! Fourth! Scram!
サル　四代目！　飛べ！
This is Lord Second's attack plan!
《これは　二代目様の手順！》
– Elder Brother!
– Mm-hmm!
兄者！
うん！
EXPLODE
Minato, get away!
ミナトよ　離れるのじゃ！
Lord Second,
you sure work fast!
二代目様は手が早い。
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
《ミナト：飛雷神の術！》
やはり　この程度では死なんか。
I suspected that might
not be enough to kill you...
穢土転生の術は　わしが作った。
それに合った戦術もな。
I created the Reanimation Jutsu,
as well as ancillary jutsu
to go with it.
Though this is the first time
I'm using it on myself.
己の体でやるのは　初めてだが…。
There it is!
The Lord Second's special...
《出るか？
二代目様考案の　互乗起爆札》
Tandem Explosive Tags!
This is how it's done!
こうやるのだ！
Each tag summons more tags,
resulting in continuous explosions.
《扉間：札が札を口寄せし続け
爆破を繰り返す…。
Concentrated and focused
consecutive explosions!
連続一点集中の爆破だ！》
This is too much!
What's going on? I can't keep up!
すごすぎるぜ！
もう　何がなんだか…。
Don't freak out!
やけに　ならない！
常に　状況を見て。
Always keep one eye on
what's happening around you!
I don't care if that is
the Jinchuriki of the Ten Tails!
十尾の人柱力だろうが
なんだろうが→
The Lords Hokage are
engaged in battle!
火影様たちが戦っておられる。
We have to join them!
我々も行くぞ！
（ダルイ）焦るな！　今は…。
Don't be hasty! We need to—!
All of you!
You must not approach heedlessly!
皆の者！
うかつに近づいてはならん。
（ダルイ）なんだ？　アイツ…。
What is he?
He's solid and swift.
《速いうえに堅い…。
And he has an attack that
turns all to dust in an instant!
そして　一瞬で　塵にする攻撃！》
Shuriken Shadow Clones!
（ヒルゼン）手裏剣影分身！
It's similar to Ohnoki's Particle Style,
but its shape is fluid.
《オオノキの塵遁に似ているが→
It can shift to be either
offensive or defensive.
形が流動的で　攻防に応じて変化し
常に保持できる》
And can be continuously maintained.
ぐっ！
I suspect it's a combination of more
than four Changes in Chakra Nature!
《おそらく　４つ以上の性質変化を
組み合わせている！
This is more than a Kekkei Genkai
or even a Kekkei Touta...
血継限界　血継淘汰の　更に上！》
But there seems to be
a time limit to how long
《だが　形態変化には
持続時間がありそうだのう》
he can use each
Change in Chakra Form.
Gramps!
じいちゃん！
Dad! You couldn't teleport
Grandpa Third with your jutsu too?
父ちゃん　三代目のじいちゃんも
父ちゃんの術で→
飛ばせなかったのかよ！？
ムリだ。
It's impossible. I can't teleport
anything that I myself,
俺自身か俺のチャクラが　間接的にでも
触れていなければ　飛ばせない。
or my chakra isn't touching directly.
Calm down, Naruto.
わめくな　ナルト！
火影たちは穢土転生だ。
The Hokage are Reanimations.
They intentionally attacked head-on
knowing that they won't die,
死なないのを　わかっていて
敵の出方や能力を分析するため→
in order to check out
the enemy's moves and abilities.
あえて　突っ込んでいったんだ。
Stop worrying and analyze
the battle instead.
あの戦いを見て
心配より　分析をしろ！
So that's Sasuke...
He's extremely smart.
《サスケ君か…　優秀な子だ》
Although it still takes a while
for a Reanimation to regenerate.
穢土転生が回復するまでには
少し　時間がかかるけどね。
I'll go first and create an opening!
まずは　俺が出て　隙を作る！
At this point, I feel the need to...
こうなっては　やはり　俺が…。
I'm done waiting, Hashirama!
もう　待ったは　なしだ。　柱間！
W-What's going on?
な…　なんだ？
I get it...
《そうか…　人柱力として　うまく
十尾が　なじんでないんだ。
Ten Tails hasn't completely
synched with its Jinchuriki yet.
This is our chance to take it down!
この状況のうちに倒す！
I'll summon my original here then!
オリジナルも　ここに！
久しぶりの
螺旋閃光超輪舞吼参式をやる！》
It's been a while, but it's time
for my Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three!
Gamakichi! Below you!
ガマ吉　下だ！
（ガマ吉）ぐっ…。
うわっ！！
He passed underground!
It's just his upper body!
地面を通って…。
上半身だけを？
Damn it!
（ミナト）しまった…。
Sasuke...
《サスケ…》
You're not the one...
お前じゃない。
... who's going to sever the past. I am!
過去を切るのは…　俺だ。
I hope this makes it in time!
間に合え…。
Flying Raijin Jutsu!
《飛雷神の術！
オビトのマーキングが消えている！？》
My markings on Obito disappeared?
Damn it!
ク…　クソッ…。
Owww...
（ガマ吉）アイテテテテ…。
ひぃ…　死ぬかと思ったってばよ。
I thought we were going to die!
I can't teleport anything
that I myself,
((俺自身か　俺のチャクラが→
or my chakra isn't
touching directly.
(間接的にでも
触れていなければ飛ばせない))
《ミナト：フフッ…　うちの子も
サスケ君に負けていないかな。
Looks like my boy is
as accomplished as Sasuke.
Now then...
さて…》
He's just like a snake.
（ガマ吉）まるで蛇じゃな。
What is that?
何だ？　あれ…。
We have to take him down
体を　うまく扱えてない。
今のうちに　やらないと。
while he's still unable
to use his body well.
くっ…　あぁっ…。
うっ…　うぅっ…。
Was he after your clone
just now, Dad?
今　父ちゃんの分身を狙ったのか？
No, I don't think that was it...
いや　どうも
そんな感じじゃなかった。
What? What happened?!
なんだ？　どうしたんだ？
自分の技を　くらってやがる。
He hit himself with his own attack.
His attack missed.
攻撃は外れたんだ。
大きすぎる十尾の力に→
Seems Obito's consciousness
is merely clinging
オビトの意識が　どうにか
へばりついているだけで→
to Ten Tail's great power.
He barely has any control over it.
まるで　コントロールできていない。
I'm glad he missed us,
外れたけん　ええけど…
くろうたら死ぬるのう…。
because if it hit us,
we'd be dead!
We can't approach him carelessly.
うかつには近づけんで…。
This time, I'll get
今度こそ
螺旋閃光超輪舞吼参式をやる！
the Rasen-Flash Super-Circle
Dance Howl Stage Three in for sure!
I'll create an opening,
隙を作るから　カンパツいれずに→
so you two hit him immediately
with your strongest combo!
お前たちのコンビ技を
叩き込むんだよ！
リン…。
Rin...
ぐあぁ！
Of course,
I'm going to be the Hokage!
((もちろん
俺は火影になんぜ！))
リン…。
Rin!
And then...
((そしたら　女にかまけてる
時間なんか　ねえんだよ。
I won't have any time for girls!
Right, Sensei?
(だろ？　先生))
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
Here I come, Obito!
いくよ　オビト。
Who... are... you?
お前…　誰…。
うおぉっ！
Finally, Sensei...
やっとだよ。　先生。
《ヤバイ！》
Damn it!
Dad!
父ちゃん！
ナルト！　構えろ！
Naruto, focus!
He got me, but I'm okay!
やられはしたけど大丈夫。
I used Flying Raijin to escape.
飛雷神で飛んだから。
どうかな？
Are you sure about that?
《いつの間に！？
そうか　俺につけて一緒に…》
When did he...?!
I see! He attached it to me so
it would teleport along with me!
koushite ima mo kawarazu
Even now, I haven't changed
donna tsuyoi nami ni mo sakarau
I'll fight any wave, no matter how strong it is
soko ni wa nakama, haruka kanata
My friends are far away
deatta subete ga ore no takara
Everyone I meet is my treasure
kono sora e habataiteku
I'll fly through this sky
ore kara shinjiru anata ni eeru
I believe in you and I'll yell out to you
toki ni wa warai naite
Sometimes I laugh or cry
donna ni fumareyouto hana wa saiteru
The flowers still bloom,
no matter how many times they've been trampled on
datte kimetakara
It's because I've made up my mind
donna ni fumarete mo saiteta hana
I'll rise up like a blooming flower
no you ni motto takaku
No matter how many times it gets trampled
sore ga naniyori mo chikara hanatsu
It unleashes more power than anything
aitsu no bun made tsuyoku ikite
I want to live resiliently for their sake too
dare ni mo makenai tsuyoi ishide
With a powerful will, I won't give in to anyone
susume kitto susumeru
Move ahead, I'm sure I'll move ahead
dare mo mitakotonai sekai wo tsukureru
I can create a world that no one has seen before
kowakunai soba ni iru kagiri
I'm not afraid, as long as you're by my side
mawari ni wa nakama ya famirii
Surrounded by friends and family
sono chikara ga michishirube ni naru
Their power shows me the way
minna kara moratta kono te ni love
In my hand, I hold what everyone has given me Love
kono machi ni fuku kaze ni noru
I'll ride the wind that blows through this city
gooru wa mada hodo tooku
I'm still a long way from my goal
demo shitteru mada yare n datte
But I know that I can still go on
dakara sakebu kono koe kareru made
So I'll cry out until I lose my voice
kono sekai wa mienu mono bakari de
This world is full of things I can't see
kowai kara jibunjishin wo kizutsuketa
I hurt myself because I was afraid of them
kirisaita yami no saki ni mieta mono
When I cut through the darkness, I saw something
massugu ni misueta mama de
I continue to gaze straight ahead
hanasanai
And never let go
Even a small power can be helpful,
because there may come
a time when it will be needed.
It all depends on how it's used.
Our power could change
the course of this world.
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
We can't afford to relax and
let our guard down
even for one second!
美空ひばりです。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"An Opening"
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Shikamaru, you would make
a great Hokage.
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
２時間スペシャル！